你被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
联系系统管理员
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
身份不明
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
身份不明
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
政府以为这些人无关紧要
The government considered these people irrelevant.
关键执行人
我们不
We don't.
失踪
关键执行人
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
状态：纽约警局任职
你永远找不到我们
You'll never find us.
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第二季 第七集
我到达地点了  芬奇
I found that address, Finch.
我到底要找谁啊
Who exactly am I looking for?
我不知该如何解释
I don't know how to explain it.
我反复核实过了  确实有个号码再次出现了
I double-checked, but it seems we have a repeat number.
再次
A repeat?
什么人会蠢到
Well, who would be dumb enough
让自己再次陷入生命危险之中
to get in a life-threatening situation again?
哥们儿
Hey, pal.
你肯定不会相信
You won't believe this.
各位
Fellas.
不管你想让这家伙受何种皮肉之苦
Whatever bodily harm you want to inflict on this guy,
我相信他都罪有应得
I'm sure he earned it,
不过就此算了吧
and I have to ask you to let it slide.
天啊里昂  你是怎么惹着这些家伙了
Jeez, Leon, what'd you do to piss these guys off?
你听说过打金吗
You heard of Gold Farming?
出售网上游戏币  换取真钱
Selling multiplayer online game currency for real cash?
风行一时
It's all the rage.
能赚大钱
People make millions.
有人对这生意非常看重
They take the business really seriously,
特别是俄罗斯黑帮
especially the Russian Mafia.
我像玩网游的人吗  里昂
Does it look like I play video games, Leon?
我的手臂好像断了
I think I broke my arm.
你把他带到这儿来了
So you brought him here?
你说有另外一个号码
You said there was another number.
我没时间处理他
I didn't have time to do anything else with him.
陶先生  我们时间有限
Mr. Tao, we don't have much time.
什么  你是谁
What? Who are you?
今晚帮我救你小命的人
The guy who helped me save your life tonight
第二次了
for the second time.
你是老大
You're the boss.
就知道约翰不是做高层管理的料
Never did figure John here for upper management.
现在有个问题  里昂
We have a problem, Leon.
我们得去处理另一件事
We have to go take care of another matter,
而俄罗斯人想要你命
and the Russians still want you dead.
所以尽管让你留在此处我颇有顾虑
So despite my misgivings about your presence,
你还是必须留下
you have to stay here.
这是哪儿
Where is here?
食物  水
Food, water.
厕所在期刊架那边
Latrine's down past the periodicals.
别开窗
Don't open any windows.
也不要打电话
And don't make any calls.
你们要我留在这里  吃微波食品
You expect me to stay here, and eat hot pockets?
如果你想活命的话
Only if you wanna live.
不许给小熊吃
Just don't feed any to Bear.
它在节食
He's on a special diet.
又是这倒霉狗
That damn dog again.
不能指望他把我的钱拉出来吧
You don't suppose any of my money came out of him?
还有  请别碰我的任何电脑设备
Oh, and please don't touch any of my computer equipment.
否则  那狗会咬死你
If you do, the dog will kill you.
真棒
Great.
那我怎么打发时间呢
What am I supposed to do for entertainment?
这是图书馆  陶先生
It's a library, Mr. Tao.
读本书吧
Try reading a book.
从这本开始
Here's a start.
刑法
我们很快回来  里昂
We'll be back soon, Leon.
告诉我  里瑟先生  你对医院有何感觉
Tell me, Mr. Reese, how do you feel about hospitals?
-从没碍过我  -很高兴听你这么说
- They've never bothered me. - I'm glad to hear it.
医院会刺激我的焦虑
They make me aggressively uneasy.
翻新之后  您肯定就认不出
After the renovations, you won't even recognize
这些老旧的手术室了
these old surgical suites anymore.
多亏了您这样出手慷慨的捐赠者
Thanks to sizable contributions from donors such as yourself,
纽约综合医院终于能拥有
New York General will finally have a surgical unit
与我们的一流医生相匹配的手术室了
as good as the talented staff of doctors who utilize it.
出手慷慨
Sizable contribution?
我出钱建了一栋楼
I helped pay for a wing...
或者两栋
or two.
否则我们要如何接近
How else were we gonna get close to--
恩耐特医生  时间刚好
Dr. Enright. Perfect timing.
先生们  这位是麦蒂琳・恩耐特医生
Gentlemen, this is Dr. Madeleine Enright,
本州顶尖的心胸和创伤外科医生
the top Cardiothoracic and Trauma Surgeon in the state.
她会监督手术室的进度
She'll be overseeing the development of the suites.
麦蒂琳  这位是哈罗德・克灵
Madeleine, this is Harold Crane,
我们的白金捐助人
one of our platinum donors,
这位是他的资产经理人  约翰・鲁尼先生
and his asset manager Mr. John Rooney.
请叫我麦蒂
It's Maddy, please.
麦蒂正是
Maddy is the kind of doctor
本院医生的杰出代表
that makes the staff here truly stand out.
那种不把眼镜缝到脸上
The kind of doctor who wouldn't find her glasses
就会找不到的医生
if they were surgically attached to her face.
那是你的么
Would those be yours there?
我就说嘛
Like I said.
抱歉  有病人在等
I'm sorry, I have a patient waiting.
我得走了
I must be going.
漂亮  芬奇
Nicely done, Finch.
佳人之眸  你我之耳
Her eyes, our ears.
先生们  很遗憾  我们也得离开了
Gentlemen, unfortunately, we must be going as well.
我们得封闭整层
We're closing off this section of the floor
进行一场非常敏感的手术
for a very sensitive surgery.
这是常规的预防措施吗
Is that a normal precaution?
这么说吧  这完全是为病人的安全着想
Let me just say it's strictly for the safety of the patient.
这个房间跟你要进行手术的房间
This room is nearly identical to the OR
几乎一模一样
that your procedure will take place in.
常规的非体外循环冠脉搭桥手术
It's a routine coronary bypass,
即不停搏的冠脉搭桥术
off-pump, "beating heart" surgery.
大约需要四五个小时
It lasts four, five hours,
你全程都将待在这个房间
and you'll be in the room the whole time.
我们虽然暂没有全套的最佳设备
Now we don't have all the best toys yet,
但我们的心导管检查
but with our coronary catheterization process,
和三维血管造影
and our 3D angiography c-arm system--
手术是完全依赖内镜吗
It's fully endoscopic?
看来你研究过手术程序了  先生贵姓
You've studied your procedures, Mister--
莱恩斯  是  我研究过了
Rains. Yes, I've studied.
小心驶得万年船
Can't be too safe,
尤其是威尔德先生还掌管着一家能源帝国
not when Mr. Veldt has an energy empire to run.
四五个小时
Four to five hours?
你们就这点本事了吗
You can't do better than that?
威尔德先生  不管你公司有多大
Mr. Veldt, regardless of how big your company is,
这场手术对你来说生死攸关
this surgery is critical for you.
需要时间
It takes time.
只要对股东和公众
As long as it remains private
保密就行
from shareholders and the public.
你签署的每一份保密协议中都有此要求
Per the multiple nondisclosure agreements you've signed.
是的  尽管我反对
Yeah, and despite my objections,
但你的手术已经被列为门诊小手术
your procedure has been listed as minor outpatient surgery.
我的团队也缩小到只剩必要人员
My team has been reduced to essential personnel,
这层楼也正在进行清空
and the floor is being cleared now.
我的团队会复查确认的
My team will make sure of that.
当然
Of course.
是啊  你的保镖已经把这儿当家了
Yeah, your security seems to have made themselves at home.
急救
Trauma!
阿尔巴尼亚黑帮为了地盘纷争火拼
Albanian gang member shot in a territorial dispute.
贯穿伤  刚从急救室出来
Penetrating trauma, fresh from emergency.
-枪伤吗  -上半身有一处枪伤
- Ballistic? - Single GSW, upper torso.
急救人员无法稳定血压
Paramedics had trouble with the BP.
收缩压70  舒张压测不到
Systolic was 70, but diastolic was impalpable.
他有枪
He's got a gun.
全都闭嘴
Everybody shut up!
你是想耍横
You wanna be a tough guy,
还是想我救你朋友的命
or you want me to save your friend's life?
护士  病人低容量性休克
Nurse, this man is in hypovolemic shock,
我想是肺不张
and I think a collapsed lung
所以会出现这种血氧饱和度读数
is what's giving those O-2 readings.
好  我们走
Okay, we're moving.
准备手术和开胸手术托盘
Prep surgery, and a thoracotomy tray.
给我个约束带  以防他咬到自己舌头
Get me a restraint before he swallows his tongue.
她看起来镇定自如
She certainly seems unflappable.
确实是
I'd say.
你确定她以前不是军医吗
You sure she was never a combat medic?
我都不确定她现在不是
I'm not so sure she isn't one now.
除了手术中的持枪黑帮  还有别的威胁吗
So what's the threat besides gun-toting gangs in surgery?
有可能来自任何方面
It could come from anywhere else:
她过去的医疗事故
a malpractice in her past;
治疗中死亡病患的家属
a bereaved relative of a patient she lost.
或者像通常一样  私生活方面的
Or as always, someone in her personal life.
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译：NoNopig  二摆舞  慕秋雪  板栗桑  didina  大黑  天朝直属
时间轴：迟迟  擦擦  GGwhywhy   特效&后期：MythCreator
初校：板栗桑  NoNopig
医学顾问：genome2k, M.D.   精校&总监：阿好
我从哥伦布转盘广场那家你喜欢的法式店
I brought you an espresso and a pain au chocolat,
给你带了浓咖啡和巧克力酥皮
from the French place on Columbus that you like.
你知道我不应该吃
Oh...you know I shouldn't.
缝合枪伤的日子例外
Except on days when you're closing up gunshot wounds.
你肯定是大清早打车才买到的吧
You must've been in a cab half the morning to get this.
你短信里说是"紧急事件"
Your text said "Emergency".
我对紧急事件非常看重
I take emergencies very seriously.
麦蒂看起来很安全  芬奇
Maddy seems safe, Finch.
她妻子叫艾米
Her wife's name is Amy.
我在一家儿童慈善机构网站上
I found her bio on the website
看到了她的简历  她是该机构执行董事
of the children's charity where she's executive director.
她们去年六月结的婚
They've been married since last June.
2011年6月纽约正式通过同性恋婚姻合法化法案
宅总扮演者ME及其夫人为表支持  曾专门拍摄反8号法案广告
那个威尔德什么时候动手术
So when does that Veldt guy go into surgery?
半个小时内
I, uh--half hour. Ugh.
天哪  我已经累死了  可还有个手术
God, I am already exhausted, and I still have that.
我今天在公园里有个艺术品募捐
I have that art fundraiser thing in the park today,
但我还是会看你的  好吗
but I'm gonna check in on you, okay?
趁机给那混蛋换个博大点的心脏吧
And try to give that jerk a bigger heart, while you're at it.
我可不是什么都能修补好
Well, I can't fix everything that's broken.
两枪  近距离
Two shots, close range?
从背后开枪有必要这样吗
That overkill when you shoot a guy in the back?
口袋都掏了
Even got his pocket lint.
-卡特  -是我
- Carter. - Hey, it's me.
有人在长岛弃尸
Someone dropped a body in Long Island city.
处决式
Execution-style.
我觉得你会想来看看的
I think you wanna come take a look.
你处理不了吗
You can't handle it?
相信我  你会想来的
Trust me, you wanna be here.
现场写有你的名字了
It's got your name all over it--
纽约警局
乔丝・卡特
警探
真写着呢
literally.
不好意思  你不能进来
I'm sorry-- you can't be in here.
但我很欣赏这里的风景
But I'm rather enjoying the view.
你在找人吗
Are you looking for someone?
是的
Yes.
找你
For you.
你是否知道据美国医学会统计
Did you know that according to the American Medical Association,
每年有九万八千人死于医疗事故
98,000 people a year die from medical error?
我不知道你是谁  但是
I don't know who you are, but--
我的名字其实无关紧要
My name, while inconsequential,
阿利斯塔・韦斯利
is Alistair Wesley.
今天  你最好犯个错误
Today, a mistake will be your best friend.
我们说说奥利弗・威尔德吧
Let's you and I discuss Oliver Veldt.
现在
Now...
你在认真看吗
Are you watching carefully?
你可爱的妻子艾米
Your lovely wife Amy.
这道红外激光来自一名枪手
The infrared laser belongs to a marksman,
如果你不想见识他的能耐
and unless you wish to see his skill,
就听好
you will listen.
奥利弗・威尔德会在手术中死亡
Oliver Veldt will not survive his surgery.
明天报纸会报道
Tomorrow, the papers will note that
尽管一流医生已竭尽全力
despite the heroic efforts of his talented surgeon,
1:15左右
at approximately 1:15,
他还是因为大量内出血身亡
he expired from a massive internal hemorrhage.
你疯了  我怎么会
You're crazy. How would I--
-我怎么能  -很简单
- How could I do that? - Very easily.
等等  里瑟先生  出事了
Wait, Mr. Reese. Something's happening.
你必须严格按我说的做
You must follow my instructions to the letter.
有人和麦蒂在一起
Someone is with Maddy.
手术进行一小时后
Exactly one hour into surgery,
你注射100毫升抗凝血剂肝素到
you will introduce 100ccs of the anticoagulant heparin
他的血液循环系统中
into his system--
急性凝血功能障碍
instant hemophilia.
三十分钟以后
30 minutes after that,
你会割伤他的左前降支
you will nick his left anterior descending artery,
他就会失血过多死在手术台上
he will bleed out on the operating table.
不  我不能  我不会
No--I can't. I won't.
如果手术因为任何原因停下
If surgery is stopped for any reason,
艾米会死
Amy dies.
如果她得到任何警示
If she is warned in any way,
她会死
she dies.
如果有警察出现在公园或者医院
If the police are called to the park or to the hospital,
她会死
she dies.
规则听明白了吗
Do you understand these rules?
很好
Excellent.
聪明的话就别试探我的底线
It would be wise not to test me in any way.
回见
Talk soon.
原来麦蒂根本不是受害者  里瑟先生
So Maddy's not the victim after all, Mr. Reese.
没错  芬奇
No, Finch.
他们要强迫她当行凶者
They're gonna force her to be the perpetrator.
这就是威胁  芬奇
That's the threat, Finch.
他们要杀奥利弗・威尔德
They're going to kill Oliver Veldt.
然而  他们要让麦蒂替他们动手
On the contrary, they're gonna have Maddy do it for them.
我们得去找她
Well, we need to get to her.
我们通不过威尔德的保镖
We'll never get past Veldt's security.
何况  只要他的保镖在
Besides, as long as his guards are around,
她在手术中应该是安全的
she should be safe in surgery.
我担心的是她妻子
It's her wife that I'm worried about.
有人守在医生这边比较好
It might be good to have someone near the doctor.
我在这里守着
I'll stay here.
我去公园看一下对艾米的威胁
I'll handle the park and assess the threat on Amy.
芬奇  你留在这儿没事吗
Finch? Are you gonna be okay here?
就算我有恐惧症  里瑟先生
Even if I had a phobia, Mr. Reese,
现在也不是发作的时候
now would not be the time for it.
死者是谁
Who's the vic?
杜山・巴比克
Guy by the name of Dusan Babic.
40岁  没有家人
40, no family,
刚从克罗地亚移民过来
recently immigrated from Croatia,
在大纽约额信托服务公司工作
worked for Greater New York Custodial Services.
只是抢劫吗
Straight-up robbery?
开始我也这么想...
That's what I thought...
但我在他身上找到了这个
till I found this on him.
我觉得没必要和其他人说
I didn't feel the need to share with others.
看背面
Check the back.
什么意思
What does that mean?
我还以为你能告诉我呢
I thought you could tell me.
你还是快走吧
Well, you might wanna get out of here
免得被人问到无法回答的问题
before people start asking questions you can't answer.
谢了
Thanks.
注射完芬太尼了  医生
Fentanyl administered, doctor.
威尔德先生  请您再签一下
Mr. Veldt, if I could ask you to sign
最后这份同意书
one last consent form.
我到底要签多少才够送出这条命的
How many forms will it take for me to sign my life away?
莉兹只是在履行她的职责  威尔德先生
Liz is just doing her job, Mr. Veldt.
任何手术都会有风险
Any surgery has its risks.
我选择全州最顶尖的外科医生以消除风险
And I chose the top surgeon in the state to eliminate them.
你最好记住了
You'd do best to remember that.
医生
Doctor?
一旦手术开始  你是打算用
Once the procedure begins, are you planning on using
隐静脉作搭桥血管吗
the saphenous vein for the bypassing channel?
不  我会使用乳内动脉接合
No, I'll use the internal mammary artery for grafts,
任何一名医学博士都会告诉你
which anyone with an MD will tell you
这是目前最佳的长效疗法
shows the best long-term results.
不过  谢谢你无谓的操心  莱恩斯先生
But thank you for your unnecessary concern, Mr. Rains.
新消息
未知号码
该行动了
医生
我在麦蒂的办公室  里瑟先生
I'm in Maddy's office, Mr. Reese.
我也许可以用她的电脑找出
With her computer, perhaps I can discover
威尔德和韦斯利之间的联系
the connection between Veldt and Wesley.
我在公园  芬奇
I'm at the park now, Finch.
看到艾米了  她的位置暴露到极点了
Got eyes on Amy, and she couldn't be more exposed.
还有好多围观者在她旁边
Lots of bystanders around here too.
依照韦斯利的规则  如果我们惊动警方
According to Wesley's rules, if we alert the police,
她就会死
she's dead.
那我们找到狙击手
Then we find the sniper.
我们还知道阿利斯塔・韦斯利什么情况
We know anything more about Alistair Wesley?
除了名字和口音吗
Besides his name and that accent?
被困在外科楼里
I can't find out anymore
我找不出任何东西
while I'm stuck here in the surgical wing.
那就有什么查什么吧
Then we'll work with what we got.
我破解了韦斯利发过来的
I was able to decode the live video
艾米在公园里的视频
of Amy in the park that Wesley sent,
所以只要麦蒂在医院里面接收
so as long as Maddy is streaming it here in the hospital,
我们就能看到
we'll be able to see it too.
图像发给你了
Sending you an image.
你能用这个三角定位狙击手位置吗
Can you use it to triangulate the sniper's position?
又不是第一次了
It wouldn't be the first time.
根据麦蒂的个人文件
From Maddy's personal file,
奥利弗・威尔德是O型阴性血
it seems that Oliver Veldt's blood type is O-negative.
如果我黑进医院的库存目录
If I can hack the hospital's inventory
让O型阴性血显示短缺
and register a shortage of O-negative blood,
纽约综合医院
血库库存
就可以推迟手术
I could stall the surgery
且不违反韦斯利的规则
without breaking any of Wesley's rules.
芬奇  我找到狙击手的位置了
Finch, I pinpointed the sniper's location.
根据激光判断  狙击手位于东北方向
Based on that laser, our sniper has a northeast position
至少是八楼以上的位置
at least eight floors up.
第三代防弹衣
Type iii ballistic body armor.
别担心  肋骨断了会愈合的
Don't worry. Those ribs'll heal.
不明身份  芬奇
No ID, Finch.
指尖上有强力胶
Super glue on his finger tips.
典型的机密行动把戏
Classic black ops trick.
你好  神秘来客先生
Hello, Mr. Mystery Guest.
韦斯利  是吗  阿利斯塔・韦斯利
Wesley, is it-- Alistair Wesley?
我不知道你是谁
I don't know who you are
也不知道你对我的同伴做了什么
or what you just did to my associate,
不过我倒是想请你喝一杯
but I'd like to buy you a drink,
否则艾米马上就会死
or Amy dies immediately.
提议不错  不过你的狙击手已经敬过酒了
That's a kind offer, but your sniper's toast.
你在虚张声势
I'll call your bluff.
你以为他是一个人
You're assuming he was alone.
各单位报到
All units check in.
红色一号  就位
Red one. Check.
红色二号  就位
Red two. Check.
等等等等
And so on and so forth.
公园拐角处有一个酒馆
There's a pub at the corner of the park.
我在那等你
I'll be seeing you.
里瑟先生  你准备怎么办
Mr. Reese, what will you do?
看来要去喝一杯了
Guess I'll go have that drink.
好吧  巴比克先生  是谁要你死
Okay, Mr. Babic, who wanted you dead,
他们又想告诉我什么呢
and what are they trying to tell me?
独居
Lived alone,
大纽约额信托服务公司工作  全勤
never missed a day of work at Greater New York Custodial.
为城里的公司提供服务
Serviced business across the city--
主要是科技公司
mostly tech companies,
包括藤真科技
including Fujima Techtronics,
位于纽约11大道66号
located at 66 11th avenue, New York.
真没看出来你还会逛公园
I didn't figure you for a day-in-the-park kind of guy.
人人都爱大自然啊  莱奈尔
Anyone can appreciate nature, Lionel.
到底什么事
So what's up?
看到那边的艺术市集了吗
See that art fair over there?
是那位美丽的年轻女士主办的
There's a nice young lady running it.
她叫艾米
Her name's Amy.
我需要你照看她一下
I need you to keep an eye on her for a minute.
什么  她惹上什么麻烦吗
What--she in some kind of trouble?
这么说吧  她被几架瞄准器瞄着呢
Let's just say she found herself in a few crosshairs.
等等  你要去哪里
Wait, where you going?
-去喝一杯  -啥
- To have a drink. - What?
这是专业团队  芬奇
This is a professional team, Finch.
把这些人弄来执行这计划
If they were brought on to execute this plan,
肯定有人付钱了
someone is paying them.
很遗憾  我今天没法扮侦探了
Unfortunately, I'm unable to play detective today,
不过我知道个合适的人选
but I know somebody perfect.
我知道奥利弗・威尔德
I-I know who Oliver Veldt is--
能源大亨  对吧
energy guy, right?
就其为半个东海岸
Energy in the sense that he supplies power
提供能源这点来说  没错
to half the eastern seaboard, yes.
有人想弄死他啊
Someone wants to flatline him, huh?
现在有一份工作  正好适合
We have a job that's a perfect fit
你这个前法务会计师来做
for a former forensic accountant.
就当是网络寻宝活动
Think of it as a digital treasure hunt.
找出企业界中  谁以威尔德为目标
Find out who would target Veldt in the corporate world,
跟踪支付职业杀手资金的流向
follow the money trail to the hit team,
帮我们从源头遏制这场阴谋
and help us stop the plot at its source.
我要怎么做
How am I supposed to do that?
去我的电脑台
Go over to my computer station.
我不能碰电脑的  记得不
I'm not supposed to touch the computer, remember?
你那只正在节食的食人兽
And your special diet man-eater
连键盘都不让我靠近
won't let me go anywhere near the keyboard.
开免提
Put me on speakerphone.
小熊
Bear?
[荷兰语]去休息
Ontspan.
昂  昂死判
Ont--ontspan?
懂外语的蠢狗  明白了
Multilingual mutt-- dig it.
先列出威尔德的敌人名单
Start by composing a list of Veldt's enemies.
威尔德死了  谁获益最大
Who stands to benefit most from Veldt's death?
是不是别的公司策划的
Did another company plot it?
那还真是重新定义了"恶意并购"
Gives new meaning to the phrase "Hostile takeover," huh?
我正在累积对你的信任  陶先生
I'm extending an element of trust to you, Mr. Tao.
请不要试探我系统的底限
Please resist the temptation to test the limits of my system.
咱像是会让你失望的人吗
Do I seem like the kind of guy who would let you down?
知道为什么优秀的酒保喜欢用大冰块吗
Do you know why a good barman favors larger ice cubes?
融化慢
They melt slower.
而且不会冲淡威士忌
And they don't dilute the whiskey,
正如一个紧凑的计划容不得半点干扰
the way a tight plan doesn't obscure its objectives.
这是防止我对你出手吗
Is that to protect you from me?
不  只是有助于对付门口你那位哨兵
No, but it might help against your sentry at the door.
填字游戏下的消音枪
The silencer poking out of his crossword section
足够露底了
was a pretty good giveaway.
我在现场处处装有监控摄像头
I have my own cameras positioned all over,
还有一组特工在那位妻子身边巡查
and a troop of operatives running recce on the wife.
分分钟都有人近到足以动手杀掉她
There's always someone close enough to kill her
只需一声令下
at a moment's notice.
所以把枪收好  喝一杯
So put away the gun and have a drink.
你是前军情六处的
I'd say you were a former MI-6,
你的队员  全是前英国空军特种部队的
and your team--all Ex-SAS.
你反应迅速
You're good on your feet,
思路清楚  判断准确
and you know your way around an asset.
前中情局的
Ex-CIA?
高手
Smashing.
-你要价多少  -恕不外售
- How much do you cost? - Not for sale.
你为威尔德工作
You're working for Veldt?
额外保镖之类的
Some kind of additional security?
这不重要
It doesn't matter.
重要的是  你被发现了
What matters is-- if you were caught,
我干嘛不杀那妻子呢
why didn't I kill the wife?
因为医生还没有违背你的规则
Because the doctor hasn't broken any of your rules yet.
确实  但我的风度是有底限的
Exactly, but my sense of propriety has its limits.
离公园远点  离那妻子远点
Now stay out of the park and away from the wife.
这不是你的游戏  没人邀请你来玩
This isn't your game, and no one's invited you to play.
别试探我的底线
Don't test me.
我预想了所有的可能
I was expecting everything.
你没预想到我
You weren't expecting me.
我们很快就准备好了  医生
We'll be ready for you soon, doctor.
新短信
艾米
我知道我的心交到你手中
就对了  医生
恩耐特医生  我不想打搅你
Dr. Enright, I hate to bother you.
你来这儿干吗
What are you doing in here?
还记得我吗  今天早前见过
Do you remember me? From earlier today?
你是那名捐赠者  克灵
You're that donor--Crane.
你可能不相信  但我知道你的妻子艾米
Look, you may not believe this, but I know your wife, Amy,
也知道你现在的困境
and I know the predicament that you're in.
我的同伴正在保护她的安全
I have an associate who's working now to ensure her safety,
你一定得相信我们
but you have to trust us.
你是谁
Who are you?
我怎么知道你不是那人的手下
How do I know you're not working for that man?
这场手术本该在二十分钟前开始
This procedure was supposed to start 20 minutes ago,
但是我更改了医院血库库存
but I altered the hospital blood records
以推迟手术
to delay the surgery.
马上就会有护士来解释这件事
In a moment, a nurse will come in here to explain the error.
现在仔细听我说
Now listen to me carefully.
我们不能让韦斯利起疑心
We can't make Wesley suspicious,
但我们会在你被迫做选择前救出艾米
but we'll save Amy before you have to make the incision.
医生  我去楼下检查过O型阴性血的库存记录了
Doctor, I checked the O-Neg records downstairs.
是电脑系统出错  他们正在修复
It's a computer mix-up. They're fixing the glitch.
库存血液很充足
We have plenty of blood reserves.
一会儿就可以开始了
We should be ready to go shortly.
莉兹  这位是克灵医生
Liz, this is Dr. Crane.
我叫他来作副手  以备不时之需
I brought him in as a second scrub if I need help.
听您安排  医生
Whatever you say, doctor.
救救我
Help me.
救救我和艾米
Help us, Amy and I.
否则我不知道自己会怎样
Or I don't know what I'll do.
麦蒂已经进入手术室了  里瑟先生
Maddy has officially gone into the operating room, Mr. Reese.
公园那边进展如何
How are things in the park?
我跟韦斯利那一杯喝得不怎么样
My drink with Wesley didn't go so well,
不过至少干掉一个他的人
but we can count another one of his operatives out.
他装了自己的摄像头
He brought his own cameras
监控了公园的每个角落
and has every inch of this park monitored.
看来他也明白监控的价值
It seems that he too knows the value of surveillance.
更糟糕的是  如果他的手下选对了
What's worse-- if he chose his people well,
我们根本无法从人群中找出潜伏者
we'll never pick his sleepers out of a crowd this big.
通道和套管都已经插好了
Ports and trocar is inserted.
我准备截取移植的乳内动脉了
I'll start the harvest of the mammary...artery.
没事吧  医生
Is everything all right, doctor?
请把摄像头往
Readjust the camera a millimeter
冠状动脉主干方向调整一毫米
along the main coronary, please.
现在怎么样  医生
How is that, doctor?
加大冲洗量
Increasing irrigation.
再抽吸
Applying more suction.
她正在往威尔德的静脉注射抗凝血剂
She's injecting the anticoagulant into Veldt's IV.
里瑟先生  我们时间不多了
Mr. Reese, we're running out of time.
里瑟先生  麦蒂正在努力坚持
Mr. Reese, Maddy's holding it together somehow,
但注射了肝素后  威尔德就是个定时炸弹
but after that injection of heparin, Veldt's a time bomb.
稍微切错一点点
any wrong incision at this point--
等等
Hold on.
陶先生  你有何发现
Mr. Tao, what did you find?
芬奇  老兄
Finch! Boobie--
我从威尔德公司网站的一个后门程序
I hacked into the Veldt Corp. servers
黑进了他们的服务器
using a back door in their website
发现了一个亿万美金的项目提案
and found a proposed multimillion-dollar project
是关于海上风电的
for offshore wind farms.
威尔德驳回了
Veldt dismissed it.
他称之为"不切实际的白日梦"
An "unsustainable pipe dream," he called it.
-这是他的原话  -里昂
- That's an actual quote... - Leon.
我给证监会的一个老酒友打了电话
I called an old drinking buddy at the SEC
他给我寄了些蓝表
who sent me blue sheets,
内容是月度股票活动追踪
monthly reports tracking stock activity.
我发现一系列针对威尔德股票的卖空行为
I found a series of short sales for Veldt's stock.
成交价非常高
It's trading at an all-time high,
看来有人赌这公司会出大事儿
so someone's betting that the company fails big.
如果股票跌了  投资人就能大赚一笔
That investor will make a fortune if the stock drops.
比如首席执行官在进行秘密手术时
For instance, if the CEO underwent a secret surgery
死在了手术台上
and died on the table.
没错
Yahtzee.
一定是韦斯利那伙人
It must be Wesley and his associates.
他们从自己的行动中捞钱
They're financing their own operation.
我从网络运营商那儿发现了有卖空纪录的服务器
I found an active server at the ISP for those short sales.
这套利机会应该值得关注
Could be an interesting arbitrage opportunity here.
我会继续查
I'll keep digging.
有发现立刻通知我
Let me know the minute you find something.
您好  医生
Hello, doctor.
仍在努力保护您的妻子
Still trying to secure your wife.
各位  我要稍事休息
Everyone, I'm going to need to take a short break
歇几分钟
for a few minutes.
您还好吗  医生
Are you all right, doctor?
我们需要找人
Do we need to get someone in here
协助手术吗
to assist with the surgery?
不用  没必要  莉兹
No, that won't be necessary, Liz.
请注意病人的体征
Please monitor the patient's vitals,
我很快就回来
and I'll be right back.
我们就不能再做点什么吗
Is there nothing more we can do?
我保证  我的同伴很快
I promise you-- my associate is close
就能解除艾米的危机了
to getting Amy out of danger.
好  我  我得歇一下
Yeah, I just-- I need a minute.
为什么停下来  医生
Why did you stop, doctor?
我想你还不明白此事的严重性
I don't think you understand how serious this is.
给你加点动力如何
How about a little motivation?
我现在会连线你的妻子
I'm going to connect you to your wife now.
你有30秒钟  记住规则
You have 30 seconds, but do remember the rules
和违规的代价
and how much you have to lose.
抱歉  我要接个电话
Ooh, sorry. I have to take this.
宝贝  我以为你在做手术呢
Hi, babe! I thought you were in surgery.
还在做
Still going.
我只是  稍歇一下  喘口气
I just, uh, took a break to catch my breath.
虽然比不上你那边
Uh, it's nothing compared to yours,
不过我这儿也是一团乱
but it's been nuts here.
捐赠者野餐会的承办人没来
The caterers didn't show for the donor picnic,
我只能勉强凑合
and I had to scramble.
抱歉  艾米  我只有一点时间
I'm sorry, Ames -- um, I only have a minute.
时间表真是  逼死人
The timetable is...killer.
我只想听听你的声音
I just wanted to hear your voice.
你还好吗
Is everything all right?
都好
Totally fine.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
坚持啊
Hang in there.
韦斯利不到一分钟就知道
Wesley knew the surgery was interrupted
手术暂停了
in less than a minute.
他在医院一定有耳目
He must have eyes and ears in that hospital somewhere.
我们别无选择了  芬奇
We don't have a choice, Finch.
我去把艾米救出来
I'm getting Amy out.
全部人都待在广场上
Everybody has to stay in the plaza
直到我们查清楚
until we work this out.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
卡特警探  凶案组的
Detective Carter, Homicide.
凶案组  你们来得真快
Homicide? You got here pretty fast.
我们几分钟前刚报警说有枪声
We just called in shots fired a few minutes ago.
还不清楚是否有尸体
I don't know if there are any bodies yet.
里面开枪了
There was shots fired inside?
好像是抢劫
Some kind of botched robbery.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
藤真科技研究工厂
Fujima Techtronics Research Facility.
警报是从研发区的无菌层传来的
Alarms went off on the clean room floor, where they do R&D.
有人进去  封了出口
Guy got inside, had his exit blocked,
开枪  保安倒地  救护车正在路上
shots fired, guards down, ambulance is on its way.
我们说话这会儿正在清空大楼
We're clearing the building as we speak.
借过
Excuse me.
各层疏散的怎么样了
What's the status on those floor evacuations?
你什么打算
So what are you thinking?
浑水摸鱼
Diversion, then extraction.
那就是你负责去摸鱼  我负责搅浑水
So if you're the extraction, I'm the diversion?
你让我怎么搅啊
What do you need me to do?
伙计  我来调查本区的一起绑架案
Hey, buddy -- I'm working an abduction in the area.
你看到可疑情况了吗
You see anything suspicious?
抱歉  警探  没看到
Sorry, Detective, I haven't,
我一上午都在巡逻
and I've been on the beat all morning.
我没允许你离开  警官
I didn't excuse you, Officer.
-什么  -你怎么回事  菜鸟吗
- What? - What are you, a probie?
我说话时你放尊重点
Have a little respect when I talk.
抱歉  长官  我什么也没看到
I'm sorry, Sir. I haven't seen anything.
我也希望能帮上您
Wish I could help.
报上你的名字  你的编号
I want your name, your badge,
你的社保号
your social security number.
你哪儿来的
Where are you from?
你哪个管区的
What precinct are you from?
冷静点  好吗
Hey, settle down, okay?
我不知道你干嘛找我麻烦  警探
I don't know why you're breaking my balls, Detective.
你是纽约警局的
You represent the NYPD?
马上把证件拿出来
I want some ID right now.
-芬奇  -陶先生
- Finch. - Mr. Tao?
够快的
That was fast.
我和小熊  那是无敌组合
Me and Bear-- we're a hell of a team.
咱虽独臂客  仍是西部第一快枪手
Even with one arm, I'm still the fastest gun in the west.
好啦  乖啦  摸摸背啦
Yes, yes, back pats all around.
有什么发现
What'd you find out?
我在偷看那个卖空的服务器
Well, I was snooping around the short seller server.
简直是个大金矿啊
That thing was a gold mine--
奥利弗・威尔德签过字的私人医疗表格
Private medical forms signed by Oliver Veldt
就躺在回收站里  你能相信吗
buried in a trash file. Would you believe that?
太有意思了
This is fun.
你和约翰就天天干这个啊
This is what you and John do all day long?
肯定内部有人告知了韦斯利
Someone on the inside must've told Wesley
关于手术的事情
about the surgery.
谁会事先知道呢
Who would've known in advance?
整件事应该是高度机密  对吧
This whole thing was supposed to be a big secret, right?
威尔德公司里知道这项手术的人
Someone in Veldt's company with knowledge of the surgery,
了解这些错综复杂
familiar with its intricacies--
陶先生  多快能把你查到的
Mr. Tao, how quickly can you send me
所有资料都发给我
everything you've dug up?
抱歉  这不是我的手机
I'm sorry, this isn't my phone--
艾米  我们时间不多了
Amy, we don't have a lot of time,
你听好
so I need you to listen.
我知道你妻子麦蒂  她是出色的外科医生
I know your wife, Maddy. She's a great surgeon.
我知道你们深爱彼此
I know you two love each other,
我知道你喜欢吃西边一家法式面包店的酥皮点心
and I know you love pastries from a French bakery on the west side.
个人感觉他们黄油放太多了
Personally, I think they use too much butter.
什么  这是怎么回事
What? What's going on?
你和麦蒂现在非常危险
You and Maddy are in a lot of danger right now,
我是来帮助你们的
but I'm here to help you.
我不明白你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
有摄像头在监视你
There are cameras watching you.
我可以引导你离开公园
I can direct you out of the park,
悄悄地不惊动那些坏人
and keep you off the radar from a lot of bad people,
但你必须跟我保持通话
but you need to stay on that phone,
仔细听我说
and listen to me very carefully.
走错一步  就全完了
One wrong step, and it's over.
讲  芬奇
Yes, Finch.
里瑟先生  根据麦蒂的时间表
Mr. Reese, according to Maddy's timetable,
两分钟内尼克・威尔德的动脉就危险了
we have less than two minutes to Nick Veldt's artery.
拜托告诉我艾米已经安全了
Please tell me you have Amy somewhere safe.
正在努力中  芬奇
I'm working on it, Finch.
斯诺探员  别动
Agent Snow--freeze.
慢慢转过来
Turn around slowly.
这里没信号
There's no signal down here.
她听不到我们
She can't hear us.
怎么回事  马克
What's goin' on, Mark?
我们没时间了
We don't have much time.
我不知道她在计划什么
I don't know what she's planning,
但你必须告诉我们的朋友
but you have to tell our friend.
那计划太大  我阻止不了
Whatever it is, it's big, and I can't stop it.
你为了盗取身份混进公司而杀人
You killed a man for his ID to get inside that company,
然后又对保安开枪
and then you shot a guard.
为什么
Why?
我别无选择
I had no choice.
这才是开始
This is just the beginning.
她已成亡命之徒  在孤注一掷
She's on a mission with nothing left to lose.
会有更多人送命
More people are gonna die.
我打电话给拆弹人员  我带你去
I'll call bomb disposal, and I'll take you in.
帮你脱身
I'll get you out of this.
她不会允许的
She won't let you.
她  她是谁
She--who is she?
莱恩斯先生  我们没多少时间了
Mr. Rains, we're on a clock--
请不要急着联系你的英国朋友
And please, don't contact your British friend
先听我说完
until you've heard me out.
英国朋友  什么东西
British friend? What is this?
一位朋友传真过来的
Faxed to me by a friend.
内容很全面
It's quite inclusive--
全部的蓝页  卖空交易  虚构公司
all the blue pages, the short sales, the fake company,
全部你透露给韦斯利的
and all that confidential medical information
机密医疗信息
that you shared with Wesley.
韦斯利  谁
Wesley? Who?
他们给你多少钱雇你做内线
How much did they pay you to be their inside man?
什么内线
Inside man on what?
谋杀你老板
The plot to kill your boss.
这些足够送你进监狱
Look, I have enough on you to send you to prison
把牢底坐穿
for a long time.
一般情况下  我就直接办了
On a good day, I just follow through with that.
今天  来笔交易
Today, I'll bargain.
我拿这些证据跟你交换
All the evidence I have in exchange
你叫停所有这一切
for your power to call this thing off.
我干嘛要杀奥利弗
Why would I wanna kill Oliver?
他痊愈之后  我们还要一起重审
After he recovers, we're supposed to re-examine
一个新的能源计划
a new energy project together.
那个风电项目  你想实现它
The wind farm project-- you want that to be a reality?
我不明白这是怎么回事  奥利弗有危险吗
I don't know what all this is. Is Oliver in danger?
如果走漏手术风声的人不是你
If that's the truth and you didn't leak news of the surgery,
那是谁
who did?
我们讨论的那个手术怎么样了  医生
How's that other operation we were discussing, doctor?
还在进行中
Still in progress.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
医生  你必须完成手术
Doctor, you have to complete the procedure.
我们必须停下
We have to stop this.
所有人  听我说
Everyone, I'm calling this--
你们全都静静离开房间
I want you all to calmly exit the room.
病人怎么办
What about the patient?
我宣布  现在我没能力完成这场手术
I'm declaring myself unfit to continue this procedure.
我先稳定住威尔德先生的情况  然后再离开
I will stabilize Mr. Veldt, and then I will follow you.
离开
Now go.
所有人  离开
Everyone--go.
里瑟先生  马上带艾米离开
Mr. Reese, get Amy out of there now.
听好
Listen up--
走向公园的40街出口
Start walking to the 40th street exit of the park.
敬酒不吃吃罚酒啊  医生
You had to do it the hard way, doctor.
游戏玩够了
Enough games.
所有单位
Calling all units--
对目标采取行动
You are green-lit on the target,
得手后撤走
then proceed to exfil.
我留下来陪你  医生
I'm staying with you, doctor.
你一个人搞不定
You can do this alone.
莉兹和我会把设备
Liz and I will move the tools
从威尔德先生的胸腔移除
from Mr. Veldt's chest cavity.
你去刷手间的橱柜里
I need you to go to the cabinets inside the scrub room
帮我取一下丙泊酚  好让他保持麻醉
and find me propofol so that we can keep him unconscious.
无论结果如何  你的选择是对的
Whatever happens, you made the right decision.
韦斯利  目标不见了
Wesley, the target is gone,
所有摄像头都没拍到她
and she's not on any of the cameras.
某人真是非常非常聪明
Then someone is very, very smart.
继续走  艾米
Keep moving, Amy.
这边
There!
就快到了
You're almost there.
-你好  我是约翰  -艾米
- Hi, I'm John. - Amy.
我们快走吧  艾米
Let's get you out of here, Amy.
警官  帮个忙  好吗
Hey, Officer, do me a favor, will ya?
告诉你公园里的搭档
Tell your partner in the park
抱歉刚才找他麻烦了
I'm sorry for busting his balls like that.
搭档  什么搭档
Partner? What partner?
公园这片就我一个人
I walk the park beat alone.
你妻子应该乖乖听话的
Your wife should've listened.
他要不行了
He's crashing.
血压在快速下降
His BP is plummeting.
出现室性心动过速
He's going into v-tach.
你肯定划破了某条动脉
You must've nicked an artery.
是你
It was you.
-你制造的伤口  -不
- You made the incision. - No.
你才是主刀  医生  我只是护士
You're the surgeon, doctor. I'm just the nurse.
或者说  是此情况下的后备计划
Or, in this case, the backup plan.
警官  关于那宗绑架案
Hey, Officer-- about that abduction.
你知道他们会伤害艾米
You knew they were going to hurt Amy.
让他死
Just let him die.
我不会让他死的
I'm not gonna let him die.
想清楚对你来说什么最重要  医生
Understand what's at stake for you, doctor.
只是一条命
It's just one life.
那也是条命
It's still a life.
陪着她
Stay with her.
我给他注射了硫酸鱼精蛋白
I gave him protamine sulfate
以恢复凝血
to coagulate his blood again...
我得让他的心脏恢复跳动
But I'm gonna have to restart his heart,
这从体外可无法进行
and I won't be able to do that from the outside.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
我要切开他  你得帮我
I'm gonna open him up, and you're gonna assist me.
我
I am?
给我那个空心手柄拉钩
Pass me that, Richardson.
就是它  你要用劲拉  好吗
That's it-- I need you to pull with a lot of pressure, okay?
我来负责乳内动脉胸骨牵开器
I'm gonna take this Finochietto retractor.
保持胸腔敞开  好的
Now, hold the chest op-- okay, yeah.
拉住了
Just keep it pulled.
我做不到
I don't think I can--
你能行
You can do it.
得把大量的血吸干净  才能找到动脉
Need lots of suction so I can see this artery.
就这样  好了
That's it. There we go.
递给我夹钳
Okay, pass me the clamp.
我先夹住这个
I'm going to clamp this now.
稍后进行缝合  阻止动脉继续出血
Suture it later to stop the arterial bleeding.
现在我要进行心脏按摩
Now I'm going to begin open heart massage.
好的
All right.
天啊
Oh, dear.
看啊
Look at it.
粘糊糊的
It's squishy.
我们成功了
We did it.
我们救活他了
We got him back.
麦
Mads.
我以为要失去你了
I thought I was gonna lose you.
不
No.
我在这里
I'm here.
我就在这里
I'm right here.
抱歉不得不如此  陶先生
Sorry for the theatrics, Mr. Tao,
但我们可不想你跑来敲门
but we couldn't have you turning up knocking on our door.
我要是为联合国儿童基金会募捐呢
What if I was collecting for UNICEF?
威尔德宣布启动海上风电计划
威尔德活下来了哈
So Veldt survived, huh?
只要他痊愈  股票就不会跌
And as long as he recovers, that stock won't dip an inch.
所有的同谋者都会承担巨额损失
All the conspirators will take a huge loss.
你们打败了坏蛋
You defeated the bad guys.
在你的帮助下
With your help.
记住这点  别惹麻烦  陶先生
Take that to mind and try to stay out of trouble, Mr. Tao.
咱可不是会让你失望的人
You know, I'm not the kind of guy that would let you down.
你觉得我们还会很快再见到他吗
Think we'll be seeing him again any time soon?
怪事年年有啊
Stranger things have happened.
这不是你的手机  里瑟先生
That's not your phone, Mr. Reese.
我从公园的狙击手那里拿的
I took it off the sniper in the park.
你好  韦斯利
Hello, Wesley.
我只是打个电话祝贺你  游戏玩得不错
I just had to call and congratulate you on a game well played.
这不是游戏
It wasn't a game.
生死攸关
Lives were at stake.
无论怎么精心计划
And after that elaborate plan,
你也不过是个普通的贼罢了
you were no more than a common thief.
你知道我远不止此
You know I'm much more than that.
我们见面之后  我发现你有点面熟
After our meeting, I knew you looked familiar.
你是约翰・里瑟
You're John Reese.
我们在伊斯坦布尔打过照面
Our paths have crossed before in Istanbul
博斯普鲁斯海峡边的市场上
at that market by the Bosphorus.
我记得那个市场
I remember the market.
但我不记得你
I don't remember you.
这才是重点
Well, that's the point.
我被刻意训练成那样的
I was trained that way for a reason.
那些难忘的岁月
Those were the days.
国际搜捕
International manhunts.
无人机袭击
Drone strikes.
我们应该找个时间喝完那杯酒
Now sometime we should finish that drink.
我确信你我之间有不少可聊的
I'm sure you and I would have a lot to talk about.
到时候见
Until then.
麻烦肯尼迪国际机场
John F. Kennedy, please.
国际航站楼
International terminal.
看起来韦斯利很享受游戏  里瑟先生
It seems Wesley enjoys a good game, Mr. Reese.
我确信我们有机会再玩的
And I'm sure we'll have the chance to play again.
藤真科技
颇做了些功课啊
Been doing a little work on the side?
我可是凶案组警探  约翰
I'm a homicide detective, John.
你知道我是做什么的
You know what I do.
如果你不想让我问问题
You shouldn't have brought me in on this
就不该把我牵扯进来
if you didn't want me asking questions.
你确定是斯诺
You sure it was Snow?
我看见他从犯罪现场溜出  穿着炸弹背心
I saw him fleeing the scene of the crime wearing a bomb vest.
他看上去绝望  无助
He looked desperate, helpless,
像是被人完全控制住了
like someone was holding him on a string.
让我告诉你"她"在计划什么事
Said to tell you that she is planning something,
大事
something big.
-谁  -我也想知道
- Who? - That's what I wanna know.
你知道这一切是怎么回事吗  约翰
Do you know what this is all about, John?
如果你知道  会告诉我吗
And if you did, would you even tell me?
你是个好警察  卡特
You're one hell of a detective, Carter.
我无法阻止你查下去
And I can't stop you from looking.
但你已经有些了解我  了解芬奇
But you already know quite a bit about me, Finch,
你也许知道  我们都曾有过至爱
and you may know we both had people who once cared about us.
现在全没了
Not anymore.
但是你
But you...
你还有你的儿子
you still have your son,
还有自己的生活
your life is still yours.
所以我想你真正要问自己的问题  警探
So I think the real question you have to ask yourself, Detective...
是你到底还想知道多少
is how much more do you really want to know?